University of Arizona Office of the President records, 1914-1937
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Homer L. Shantz Papers, 1928-1936
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1928-1936
    - Requests for information about students. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Requests for information about scholarships, fellowships, and research. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Requests for various information regarding buildings, curricula, governing board, military, and financial matters. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Requests for opinions. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Requests for opinions. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Requests for endorsements, support, and greetings. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Requests for endorsements, support, and greetings. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Requests for miscellaneous information on various subjects, publications, pictures, etc. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Invitations to send to delegates or to participate. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Invitations to attend, accepted. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Invitations to attend, declined. 1928-1936 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Depression Problems and Federal Relief Problems, 1928-1936
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with U.S. Congress. 1932-1936 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Congress, Isabella Greenway. 1932-1937 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Emergency Council. 1932 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Arizona State Planning Board correspondence. 1934-1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Arizona State Planning Board correspondence. 1934-1936 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Arizona State Planning Board meeting minutes. 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Civil Works Administration, Includes note amusing C.W.A. "project" suggested by W.M. Gohring, enclosed letter to Jane Rider, April 4, 1934. 1933-1934 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps work, Includes Saguaro National Monument, University Indian Ruins, and correspondence with Senator Carl Hayden. 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Pima County Reconstruction Finance Corporation Relief Fund. 1932-1933 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Pima County Welfare Board. 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - UA Unemployment Fund and Tucson Emergency Relief Committee. 1931-1933 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Federal Emergency Relief Administration: Student Employment. 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - National Youth Administration; Student Employment. 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Works Progress Administration. 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Subsistence Homesteads and Rural Homes in Arizona, Inc. 1933-1935 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Federal Aid Projects. 1933-1936 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Professional Organizations, 1928-1936
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science. 1929-1933 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - American Association of University Professors, Includes the cases of Professors H.L. Bakhuysen, A.F. Hemenway, and Horace Gunthorp. 1928-1936 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - American Association of University Women. 1929-1935 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - American Civic Association, Inc. 1934-1936 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - American Council on Education. 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Association of American Universities. 1931-1933 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Association of Colleges and Universities of the Pacific Southwest. 1931 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities. 1929-1936 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities. 1929-1936 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities. 1929-1936 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities. 1929-1936 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - National Association of State Universities. 1928-1935 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - National Student Federation. 1931-1932 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools. 1930-1935 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Arizona Educational Scene, 1928-1936
    - Superintendent of Public Instruction. 1928-1936 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Superintendent of Public Instruction. 1928-1936 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - State Board of Education meeting minutes. 1931-1936 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - State Board of Education meeting minutes. 1931-1936 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - State Department of Vocational Education. 1928-1936 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Grady Gammage. 1928-1935 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Thomas J. Tormey. 1933-1936 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - John R. Murdock, book on history and government of Arizona. 1928-1929 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Legislative Amendment: Central Control of School Systems of the State. 1929 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Yuma High School Controversy. 1929-1930 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Inter-Institutional Agreements. 1931-1932 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Legislative Amendment 100-101: Limiting State Expenditures. 1932 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - J.W. Hoover. Arizona Supplement to State text on Geography. 1931-1935 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Junior Colleges. 1933-1934 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Arizona Groups and Topics, 1928-1936
    - Arizona Cattle Growers Association. 1929-1936 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Arizona Children's Colony Building Site. 1929 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Arizona Pioneers' Historical Society, Includes correspondence regarding the Arizona Historical Review. 1932-1935 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Industrial Congress. 1928-1930 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Arizona State Industrial School, Fort Grant. 1933 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Arizona State Laboratory Reports. 1928-1936 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Colorado River and Boulder Dam. 1929-1934 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Copper Tariff. 1931, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - U.S.S. Arizona. 1928,1934 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Yuma-Gila Project. 1935-1936 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Events, 1928-1936
    - Inauguration. April 24, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Commencement. 1929-1936 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Mothers' and Dads' Day. 1934-1935 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Mothers' and Dads' Day. 1934-1935 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Field Course in Ecology, Flagstaff. Summer 1929 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - N.I. Vavilov's Visit to Arizona. October 1930 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Northern Arizona State Fair, Prescott. July 1931 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - George Washington Bicentennial. 1931-1933 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Century of Progress, Chicago, Illinois. 1933-1934 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - California Pacific International Exposition, San Diego, California. 1935 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Scientific Interests and Projects, 1929-1936
    - Carnegie Institution in Washington. 1927-1935 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - U.S.D.A. Bureau of Biological Survey. 1928-1936 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - U.S.D.A. Bureau of Biological Survey, Quail Research Project, Includes correspondence with Aldo Leopold and others. 1928-1934 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - U.S.D.A. Bureau of Plant Industry. 1928-1935 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - U.S.D.A. Bureau of Plant Industry. 1928-1935 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - U.S.D.A. Forest Service. 1928-1936 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - U.S.D.A. Forest Service. 1928-1936 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - U.S.D.A. Forest Service, Kiabab Deer Herd Investigations. 1931 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - U.S. National Park Service. 1931-1935 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Reforestation Project, Includes correspondence with Govenor B.B. Moeur and Senator Carl Hayden. 1933 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Saguaro Cactus Forest. 1928-1936 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Soil Erosion Projects. 1928-1936 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Houserock Valley Wildlife Refuge. 1934 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence with Botanists, Zoologists, etc. Includes offer to HLS to become head of the Botany Department at the University of Minnesota, 1931. 1927-1935 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding plants, cactus, and gardens. 1927-1936 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding vegetation maps. 1930-1936 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Scientific Meetings, 1928-1936
    - Fifth International Botanical Congress, Cambridge, England. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - First International Congress on Soil Science, Moscow, Russia. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Conference on Wildlife, Forest, and Range Problems, Tucson, Arizona. 1930 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Conference on Wildlife, Forest, and Range Problems, Utah. 1931 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Diary, mostly blank, entries for January 2, February 3, February 27, March 8, and August 11-26, 1935 appear to be notes made while attending unidentified meetings. 1935 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Committees, 1928-1936
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee correspondence. 1931-1935 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - National Land-Use Planning Committee. No Date (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - National Land-Use Committee meeting minutes. 1932-1933 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - National Land-Use Committee meeting minutes. 1932-1933 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - National Land-Use Committee meeting minutes. 1932-1933 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Committees, Memberships, Talks, etc, 1928-1936
    - Arizona Advisory Committee on Illiteracy. 1931-1932 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Various Committees. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Memberships. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Talks, requests excepted and declined. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Talks, requests excepted and declined. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Talks, requests excepted and declined. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Talks, requests excepted and declined. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Talks, requests excepted and declined. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous material for talks. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Statements for publications. 1928-1936 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding publications by HLS. 1928-1937 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Series V: Paul S. Burgess Papers, 1936-1937
  - Miscellaneous and general correspondence. August 1936-June1937 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Govenor Benjamin B. Moeur and Govenor R.C. Stanford. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Faculty, miscellaneous. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Faculty: Dean of Liberal Arts, E.R. Riesen. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Faculty: Dean of Women, Evelyn W. Jones. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Faculty: Drama, Marguerite Marrow. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Faculty: Byron Cummings, head archaeologist for the Arizona State Museum. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Students, miscellaneous. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Commencement. 1937 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Department of Health. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Financial Papers. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Military and R.O.T.C. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Mormon Institute. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Radio Broadcasting, proposal of KVOA. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Restoration of Old Fort Lowell, includes Saguaro National Monument and University Indian Ruin. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Rulings of the Attorney General. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Works Progress Administration Projects. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Congress. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Arizona State Legislature. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - State Board of Education meeting minutes and Superintendent of Public Instruction correspondence. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Arizona State Laboratory. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Association of Land Grant Colleges and Universities. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - North Central Association. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Requests for information about the University of Arizona. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Various requests. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Invitations to speak, attend, become a member, etc. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Paul S. Burgess Statements. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Regents. 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 29)